谁在那里？
Who's there?
山姆，我们来救你了
It's your relief, Sam.
- 情况怎么样？ - 长官，没有任何发现
- All quiet? - Didn't see a thing, chief.
其他人也没有发现
Nobody ever does.
不管那家伙是什么东西，它已经杀了50个人了
Whatever the thing is, it's already killed 50 people.
我还从没想过这下面居然这么黑
Never realised before how dark it is down here.
施密特，要保持警惕
Stay on your toes, Schmitter.
手里要一直握着枪
Keep your phaser in your hand at all times.
那样又有什么用呢？你看到发生在艾德·阿佩尔身上的事了
What good will that do? You saw what happened to Ed Appel
他打中了那个怪物
when he took a shot at the thing.
在那个怪物伤害到其他人之前
How about all those other people,
- 他们又能做得了什么呢？ - 抱歉，施密特
- before the monster got them? - I'm sorry, Schmitter.
我懂你的感受，但是我们还是要做好防备
I know how you feel, but we've got to have guards.
好的，长官
Okay, chief.
我会尽力的
I'll do what I can.
保持警惕
Keep alert.
如果你听到或者看到什么东西，就呼叫我们
If you hear anything or see anything, call in.
会有人在三分钟之内赶到这里的
Somebody can be here in three minutes.
三分钟内，很多事情都可能发生
A lot can happen in three minutes.
长官，进取号正在赶往这里，是真的吗？
Chief, is it true the Enterprise is on its way?
他们就要来了
It's coming.
你觉得他们能在四小时内赶来吗？
Think it could get here in the next four hours?
你会没事的
You'll be all right.
快跟我来！
Come on!
施密特
Schmitter.
就像其他人一样…
Like the rest of them...
…被烧焦了
...burned to a crisp.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命和新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：sholto
校对：诸星龟龟
第一季第二十五集
黑暗中的魔鬼
船长日志，星历3196.1
Captain's log, stardate 3196.1.
从杰纳斯6号行星钚介钼生产站发出的求救呼叫
A distress call from the pergium production station on Janus VI
将进取号指引向了那个历史悠久的殖民地
has brought the Enterprise to that long-established colony.
我和史波克先生，麦考伊医生
Mr. Spock, Dr. McCoy and I
传送下来与总工程师范登堡见面
have beamed down to meet with Chief Engineer Vanderberg,
他也是杰纳斯6号行星上的执行长官
administrative head of Janus VI.
好吧，让我们先假设有一头怪物
All right, let's assume there is a monster.
它做了什么？
What has it done?
事情是从什么时候开始的？
When did it start?
大概三个月前，我们打通了新的地层
About three months ago, we opened up a new level.
传感器显示那里有异常丰富的钚介钼资源
Sensors gave us an unusually rich pergium reading.
不仅仅是钚介钼，那里几乎有你想要的任何东西：
Not only pergium, whatever you want:
铀、铈、铂
uranium, cerium, platinum.
整颗行星都蕴含着那样的资源
The whole planet's like that.
那简直就是一间珍宝屋
It's a treasure house.
好的，我们知道了
Yes, we're aware of that.
如果不是挖掘的条件过于困难
If mining conditions weren't so difficult,
杰纳斯6号能够为1000颗行星提供物质原料需求
Janus VI could supply the mineral needs of a thousand planets.
但是到底发生了什么事？
But what happened?
起初，自动机械开始一点点地
First, the automatic machinery, piece by piece,
几乎解体
started to almost disintegrate.
金属开始融化
Metal began dissolving away.
完全找不出原因
There was no reason for it,
我们的化学家也不能分析出腐蚀的原因
and our chemists were unable to analyse the corrosive agent.
我确信这一切都是有原因的
I'm sure there is an answer.
只是还没有被发现
It simply has not yet been discovered.
是的
Yes, it has.
我不知道那头残忍的怪物是什么
I don't know what this butchering monster is,
但我知道它都干了些什么
but I know what it's doing.
我们的维护工程师，被派到漂流物中
Our maintenance engineers, sent down into the drifts
维修被腐蚀的设备
to repair the corroded machinery.
我们最后找到了他们，都被烧焦了
We found them, seared to a crisp.
是不是火山喷发造成的？
Volcanic activity?
舰长，这段时间这座星球上没有火山活动
There is no current volcanic activity on this planet, captain.
他是对的，没有火山活动
He's right. None.
起初，伤亡事件都是发生在底下深处
At first, the deaths were down deep,
但是现在逐渐向我们所在这层发展
but they've been moving up toward our levels.
上一个人是在三天前死的，就在这里往下三层的地方
The last man died two days ago, three levels below this.
是同样被烧死的吗？
The same way, burned?
我要去检查下尸体
I'd like to examine the body.
我们为你保留了尸体，没剩下多少东西
We kept it for you. There isn't much left.
罗伯茨会带你去的
Roberts will show you.
他走得一点也不安详
It isn't pretty.
你派了哨兵或警卫吗？
You post sentries, guards?
当然，他们中有5个人已经死了
Of course. Five of them have died.
- 谁还见过那个怪物？ - 我
- Who else has seen this? - I have.
他是艾德·阿佩尔，首席执行工程师
This is Ed Appel, chief processing engineer.
- 你描述一下它的样子 - 我不能
- Describe it. - I can't.
我只是匆匆一瞥
I only got a glimpse of it,
它体型很大，身上长满了毛发
but it's big and shaggy.
艾德打中了它
Ed shot it.
你是说他向它开枪了？
You mean shot at it.
不，我是说打中了，用这个
No, I mean shot it, with this.
- 有意思 - 正中目标
- Fascinating. - A good, clean shot.
甚至都没有让它减速
Didn't even slow it down.
嗯，我已经向你做了报告
Well, I've made my report to you.
生产停止了，没有人愿意到底层去
Production has stopped. Nobody will go into the lower levels,
我不会责备他们，如果联邦政府还想要钚介钼
and I don't blame them. If the Federation wants pergium,
那你们就要解决这件事情
then you're gonna have to do something about it.
我们就是来解决问题的，范登堡先生
That's why we're here, Mr. Vanderberg.
你们武装力量很强大，是不是？
You're all pretty tough, aren't you?
星舰、相位炮组…
Starship, phaser banks...
但是你不能把你的星舰开到隧道里
You can't get your starship down in the tunnels.
我不认为有那个需要
I don't think there will be any need.
范登堡先生，我需要一份详尽的地下建筑图表
Mr. Vanderberg, I'll need a complete subsurface chart
包括所有的漂流物、走廊和隧道
of all the drifts, galleries, tunnels.
- 我这就给你 - 范登堡先生，这是什么？
- You'll get it. - Mr. Vanderberg, what is this?
这是一个硅结核
It's a silicon nodule.
在这地底下有几百万个，没有什么商业价值
They're a million of them down there. No commercial value.
但是，至少在地理学上是件怪事
But a geological oddity, to say the least.
都是由硅组成的吗？
Pure silicon?
还有一些微量元素
A few trace elements.
听着，我们不是请你们来收集石头的
Look, we didn't call you here so you could collect rocks.
谢谢，范登堡先生，我们需要你的通力合作
Thank you, Mr. Vanderberg. We'll need your complete cooperation.
我会全力配合的
You'll have it.
不管它是什么东西，一定要找到那个怪物
Just find that creature, whatever it is.
我还有事情要去做
I've got a quota to meet.
来吧，阿佩尔
Come on, Appel.
大量的隧道会让我们的搜寻变得更加艰难
A vast number of tunnels is not gonna make our hunting any easier.
- 医生？ - 吉姆，施密特不是被烧死的
- Doc? - Schmitter didn't burn to death, Jim,
- 至少不是通常意义上的“烧死” - 给我们解释一下
- not in the usual sense, anyway. - Explain that.
嗯，尸体只有骨头的碎块和牙齿保留了下来
Well, there were only fragments of bone and teeth left,
这里的物理学家也同意我的观点
but the plant's physician agrees with me.
是化学腐蚀
A chemical corrosion,
就像是他被扔进了装满强腐蚀性酸液的容器一样
almost as if he'd been thrown into a vat of extremely corrosive acid.
那种酸能腐蚀机械设备吗？
Strong enough to eat machinery?
那种酸能腐蚀你能想到的所有东西
Strong enough to eat anything else away you can think of.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
我已把发生死亡事件和破换活动的地点绘制成表
I've charted the position of the deaths and the acts of sabotage.
这里，这里还有这里
Here, here and here.
如果这些事件发生的时间是准确的话
If the times of these incidents are to be accepted as accurate,
那个生物一定有不可思议的速度
the creature would have to have moved at an incredible rate of speed.
范登堡先生，这些表格是什么时候做的？
Mr. Vanderberg, how recent are these charts?
表格是去年做的
They were made last year.
是在那个生物出现之前？
Before the appearance of whatever it is?
- 是的 - 我知道了
- That's right. - I see.
史波克先生，给我们讲一下地表下面的生物情况
Mr. Spock, give us a report on life beneath the surface.
在我们探测器的扫描范围之内，没有生命迹象
Within range of our sensors, there is no life,
地底下也没有这个殖民地
other than the accountable human residents of this colony
所谓的人类居民
beneath the surface.
至少没有我们知道的生命形式
At least no life as we know it.
我们不能靠走路一条通道一条通道的搜寻
We can't cover tunnel by tunnel on foot.
我们必须要重新开始生产
We must get production going again.
我们一定要开采到钚介钼
We must have that pergium.
舰长，如果我们能迫使那个生物再次出现…
Captain, if we could force another appearance of this creature...
每当那个生物出现，就会有人死亡
When that creature appears, men die.
隧道太多了
Too many tunnels.
我们不可能——
We couldn't possibly--
史波克先生，我们的探测器可以在相当远的距离
Mr. Spock, our sensors can pick up normal life functions
搜寻到正常生命形式的信号
at a considerable distance,
但是如果是非正常生命形式呢？
but what about abnormal life functions?
反应室出现了状况
Something's happening in the reactor room!
回到岗位上去
Back to your stations.
看那个
Look at that.
舰长，不要碰那个
I wouldn't touch it, captain.
它具有极强的腐蚀性
An extremely active corrosive.
痕迹上或许还残留有腐蚀性
Traces may linger.
寇克，快来！
Kirk, quickly!
整个反应堆的主循环泵不见了
The main circulating pump for the entire reactor, it's gone.
舰长，探测器显示门上面也有相同的物质
The same indications shown at the door, captain,
- 非常强的腐蚀性 - 有可以替换的东西吗？
- a very strong corrosive. - Is there a replacement for that?
没有，这个反应堆过时了，但是从来没出过状况
No, none. It's outdated. But we've never had any trouble with it.
史波克，船上有吗？
Spock, onboard?
舰长，这件设备太古老了，没有合适的器件
Nothing for a device this antiquated, captain.
没有泵装置，这座反应堆会爆炸
Without the pump mechanism, the reactor will go supercritical.
这会污染半个星球，我们不能关闭它
It could poison half the planet. We can't shut it down.
它为整个殖民地提供热量、空气和生活补给
It provides heat and air and life support for the whole colony.
史波克先生，看来我们被给与了一次机会
Mr. Spock, we seem to have been given a choice.
要么死于窒息
Death by asphyxiation,
要么死于放射性污染
or death by radiation poisoning.
是一个PXK钚介钼反应堆吗？
A PXK pergium reactor?
长官，我们没有多余的这种类型的循环泵了
No, sir, we don't have any spare circulating pump for a thing like that.
我有20多年没见过PXK了
I haven't seen a PXK in 20 years.
你能制作一个吗？这很重要
Can you rig one up? It's vital.
嗯，长官，我或许能组装一个
Well, sir, I can put together some odds and ends,
但是不能持续太长时间
but it won't hold for long.
多久？
How long?
运气好的话，或许能坚持48小时
Forty-eight hours, maybe, with a bit of luck.
有48个小时总比没有强
Forty-eight hours is better than nothing.
带齐你要的东西，传送到这里来
Get together what you need and beam down here with it.
- 这是首要任务 - 好的，舰长
- Top priority. - Aye, captain.
我这就下来，史考特，通话完毕
I'll be right down. Scott, out.
如果反应堆爆炸，会发生什么情况？
What happens when it breaks down?
幸运的话，我们会在那之前找到丢失的部分
Hopefully, we'll have found the missing part by then.
- 幸运的话？我觉得可能性很小 - 长官，我们必须那么做
- Hopefully? Small chance. - We'll have to, chief.
也可以选择把你的人都传送到进取号上
The alternative is to evacuate all your people up to the Enterprise.
很多星球都依赖你
A dozen planets depend on you
为他们的反应堆提供钚介钼，他们已经在痛哭了
for pergium for their reactor. They're already screaming.
反应堆正在关闭，生命保障系统失灵——
Reactors closing down, life-support systems failing--
寇克，我很担心我在这里的下属
I'm concerned with my people right here, Kirk.
他们正面临着被杀
They're being murdered.
你一定要找到那个怪物，杀死它
You find that monster and kill it.
那个丢失的循环泵并不是无意中被拿走的
The missing pump was not taken by accident.
那是整个设备中极其重要的一部分
It was the one piece of equipment absolutely essential
对反应堆的运行至关重要
for the operation of the reactor.
你认为那个生物想把我们驱逐出这颗星球？
You think the creature is trying to push the colonists off the planet?
看起来是这样
It would seem so.
但是，为什么是现在呢，史波克先生？
But why now, Mr. Spock?
这些生产设备已经运行超过50年了
These production facilities have been in operation for over 50 years.
我不知道
I don't know.
但是有一种可能性
But there is a possibility.
是什么呢？
What's that?
据我们所知
Life, as we know it,
生命通常都是基于碳化合物的组合
is universally based on some combination of carbon compounds.
但是如果存在基于其他元素的生命形式呢？
But what if life exists based on another element?
比如说，硅元素
For instance, silicon.
史波克先生，你是在胡说
You're creating fantasies, Mr. Spock.
不一定，我听过基于硅元素生命形式的
Not necessarily. I've heard of the theoretical possibility
理论可能性
of life based on silicon.
但是基于硅元素的生命形式会是完全不同的形态
But silicon-based life would be of an entirely different order.
很可能我们的相位枪对它没有作用
It's possible that our phasers might not affect it.
当然不是一号相位枪，它比二号相位枪的威力要逊色的多
Certainly not phaser one, which is far less powerful than phaser two.
好的
All right.
这样怎么样？
How about this?
一个生活在我们星球深处的生物
A creature that lives deep in the planet below us,
在坚硬的岩石里筑巢
at home in solid rock.
我觉得为了生存
It seems to me that in order to survive,
它应该有某种形式的天然盔甲
it would have to have some form of natural armour plating.
这就能解释很多事情
It could explain much,
尤其是殖民地人员只配备了一号相位枪
especially since the colonists are armed only with phaser one.
但是我们有二号相位枪
But our people have phaser two.
而我能够对它进行调整，使之面对硅时更有威力
Which I could adjust to be more effective against silicon.
硅基生物在生理上是不可能的
Silicon-based life is physiologically impossible,
特别是在有氧的环境下
especially in an oxygen atmosphere.
医生，或许是这样的
It may be, doctor,
在这样的大气环境下，那个生物可以出现很短时间
that the creature can exist for brief periods in such an atmosphere
之后再回到自己的环境中
before returning to its own environment.
我还是认为你在异想天开
I still think you're imagining things.
医生，你或许是对的，但是至少我们有继续搜寻的方向了
You may be right, doctor, but at least there's something to go on.
史波克先生，通知乔托少校
Mr. Spock, have Lieutenant Commander Giotto
集合安全部队
assemble the security troops
并给他们配备二号相位枪
and arm them with phaser number two.
你要做适当的调整
You make the proper adjustments.
你看起来对这块石头很痴迷
You seem fascinated by this rock.
是的，舰长
Yes, captain.
你回想一下范登堡说的话
You recall that Vanderberg commented
在底层有成千上万个这种东西
there were thousands of these at a lower level.
就在那个生物首次出现前
The level which the machinery opened
机器所开启的那层
just prior to the first appearance of the creature.
他们有联系吗？
Do they tie in?
- 我不知道 - 那就推测一下
- I don't know. - Speculate.
麦考伊医生已经取笑我了
I have already given Dr. McCoy sufficient cause for amusement.
我还是好好考虑一下这件事情的可能性
I would prefer to cogitate the possibilities for a time.
不要太长时间，史波克先生
A short time, Mr. Spock.
我们没多少时间了
We have very little.
怎么样了，史考特？
How's it going, Scotty?
嗯，长官，这简直就是堵漏工人的噩梦 但是它还能坚持一段时间
Well, sir, it's a plumber's nightmare, but it'll hold for a bit.
它一定要坚持更长时间
It has to hold longer than a bit.
对不起，长官，我尽力了
I'm sorry, sir, that's about the best I can do,
我保证它还不够好
and I guarantee it's not good enough.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长
- Kirk here. - Captain,
安全部队已经在范登堡长官的办公室集合了
the security officers have gathered in Chief Vanderberg's office.
我会尽快赶到的，寇克，结束通话
I'll be right there. Kirk, out.
史考特，再加把劲
Scotty, ride herd on it.
良言相劝，细心呵护
Kind words, tender-loving care.
尽你一切所能，让它运转起来
Kiss it, baby it, flatter it if you have to, but keep it going.
我会尽力的，长官
I'll do what I can, sir.
你们要一层一层的进行，搜索通道的每寸地方
You'll proceed from level to level, checking out every foot of opening.
你们要寻找某种生物
You are searching for some sort of creature
它对相位枪有较强的抵抗性
which is highly resistant to phaser fire.
你们的相位枪要调到最大威力
Your phasers will be set on maximum.
要记住，已经有50个人死掉了，我不希望再有伤亡
And remember this, 50 people have died. I want no more deaths.
除了那个残忍的怪物
Except the bloody thing.
我不确定那个生物会不会一看到你们就发动进攻
The creature may or may not attack on sight.
但是，你们必须那样做
However, you must.
我们要尽快恢复生产，这很重要
It is vitally important that we get this installation back into production.
范登堡先生，我能问你
Mr. Vanderberg, may I ask at which level
你在哪一层发现硅结核的？
you discovered the nodules of silicon?
23层，为什么问这个？
The 23rd. Why?
乔托少校，带上你的队伍，直接去第23层
Commander Giotto, take your detail, go directly to the 23rd level,
- 在那里开始搜寻 - 好的，长官
- start your search there. - Aye, aye, sir.
我能问你为什么怀疑
May I ask if you have reason to suspect
那个生物在23层的原因吗？
this creature may be on that level?
这是我们讨论的一种可能性
It's one of the possibilities we've discussed.
我要求你的属下都留在顶层
I want your people to stay on the top level,
- 不要分散，待在安全的地方 - 舰长，我不知道什么地方安全
- together and at a safe place. - I don't know any safe place, captain.
事情发生和结束的方式…
The way that thing comes and goes...
嗯，先生们，根据分派的任务，出发吧
Well, gentlemen, you have your instructions. Let's get at it.
史波克先生，有什么发现吗？
Mr. Spock, find something?
舰长，我正在调整三录仪以便更好地对硅进行探测
Adjusting my tricorder to register for silicon, captain.
- 有意思 - 发现什么痕迹了吗？
- Interesting. - Traces?
舰长，发现一个生物
A life form, captain.
水平方向111度，垂直方向4度
Bearing, 111 degrees. Elevation, four degrees.
- 是我们的人吗？ - 不是，长官，它的身体是由硅组成的
- One of our people? - No, sir, silicon.
舰长，他连发射的机会都没有
He never even had a chance to fire, captain.
从听到他呼救到我们赶来，只有几秒钟
It's only been seconds since we heard him scream.
那个生物一定就在附近
The creature must still be around.
舰长
Captain.
看这个通道，我的探测仪显示
This tunnel. My readings indicate
通道开通不超过一小时，实际上可能刚被打通
it was made within the hour. Moments ago, in fact.
- 你确定？ - 是的
- Are you certain? - Positive.
这条通道很深
This tunnel goes back as far as the eye can see.
我们最好的设备也不能打通这样一条通道，即使使用相位枪
Our best machinery couldn't cut a tunnel like this, not even with phasers.
是的，舰长，我有点困惑了
Indeed, captain. I'm quite at a loss.
消失了
Gone.
失踪了
Disappeared.
真令人吃惊，体型那么大居然能移动这么快
Astonishing that anything of that bulk could move so rapidly.
- 这些墙温度很高 - 是的
- These walls are hot. - Indeed.
这条通道是在两分钟之前被打通的
This tunnel was cut within the last two minutes.
舰长，你还好吧？
You all right, captain?
是的，我很好
Yes, perfectly.
- 看见它了吗？ - 是的，我们看见了
- Did you see it? - Yes, we saw it.
这条通道通向哪里？
Where does this tunnel go?
探测器显示那个方向有一个由这种通道组成的迷宫
Readings indicate a maze of tunnels of this general category in that direction.
- 你打中它了吗？ - 是的，我们把它打伤了
- Did you get a shot at it? - Yes, we took a bite out of it.
不像是动物组织
Not animal tissue.
那是什么？
What is it?
我觉得最可能是石棉纤维
The closest approximation I could come to would be fibrous asbestos.
- 舰长，那是一种矿石 - 那么你的猜测是正确的
- A mineral, captain. - Then your guess was right.
看起来是这样
It would seem so.
硅基生物
Silicon based.
让我们来理清思路
Summation.
我们正面对一种生活在岩层深处的硅生物
We are dealing with a silicon creature of the deep rocks,
它能够在岩石中自由穿行，像我们在空气中一样
capable of moving through solid rock as easily as we move through the air.
- 这就能解释那些通道的形成了 - 说得对
- That would account for the tunnels. - Correct.
这种生物的身体能产生强腐蚀性酸液
This creature's body secretes an extremely powerful corrosive.
足以溶解反应室的门
Powerful enough to dissolve the door of the reactor chamber.
这也解释了被它杀害的人的死状
And it explains the murdered men.
它的身体一定对相位枪有抵抗作用
It's definitely phaser resistant.
我们针对硅的特性调整了武器，并使用了最大火力
We had our weapons set for silicon and on full power,
但是我们只是打伤了它，它还活着
yet we only damaged it. It still lives.
你是说，我们杀不了它？
You mean, it's impossible to kill.
不，要杀它，或许需要几把相位枪同时射击
No. No, it might require massed phasers.
或者一把相位枪长时间射击
Or a single phaser with much longer contact.
少校…
Commander...
…把这个消息带给你的属下
...pass this on to your men.
我们知道那个生物就是凶手，现在它受伤了
We knew it was a killer, now it's wounded.
或许吃痛得躲在某个地方
Probably in pain somewhere back there.
没有什么比受伤的野兽更危险的了
There's nothing more dangerous than a wounded animal.
乔托少校
Commander Giotto,
让你的属下在这块区域重点搜寻
instruct your men to concentrate the search in this sector.
提醒他们那个生物受伤了
Remind them that the creature is wounded.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
史波克先生，你在做什么？
What is it, Mr. Spock?
舰长，我对所有生命形态进行了全面的球形调查
I've run a complete spherical check on all life forms, captain,
半径100英里
radius 100 miles.
我发现了我们的人，所有人
I've located our men, all of them.
并且我还发现了一个生物
And I've located one creature
在天然岩层中快速移动，水平方向201度
moving rapidly through native rock. Bearing, 201,
这就是我的发现
and that is all.
- 100英里内有一个生物？ - 正是这样
- One creature in 1 00 miles? - Exactly.
舰长，据统计单单这个普通区
Captain, there are literally thousands of these tunnels
就有数千条这样的通道
in this general area alone.
用尽那个生物的一生时间也不可能打通那么多通道
Far too many to be cut by the one creature in an ordinary lifetime.
那么根据你的三录仪数据
Then we're dealing with more than one creature
我们要面对的就不只是一个生物
despite your tricorder readings.
或者说面对一个有着漫长生命的生物
Or we have a creature with an extremely long life span.
或者它是打通这些通道的那个种族的
Or it is the last of a race of creatures
最后一个生物
which made these tunnels.
这样的话，如果它是一个逝去种族的唯一幸存者
If so, if it is the only survivor of a dead race,
那么杀了它是违背科学的罪过
to kill it would be a crime against science.
史波克先生…
Mr. Spock...
…我们的任务是保护殖民地
...our mission is to protect this colony,
让钚介钼的生产恢复，我们不是在进行动物学研究
to get the pergium moving again. This is not a zoological expedition.
继续监视那个生物的动向
Maintain a constant reading on the creature.
需要的话，我们就要用相位枪打通我们自己的通道
If we have to, we'll use phasers to cut our own tunnels.
我们包围它
We'll try to surround it.
抱歉，史波克先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Spock,
但是我想那个生物一定会死
but I'm afraid the creature must die.
舰长，我也那样认为
I see no alternative myself, captain.
真是可惜了
It merely seems a pity.
搜寻小组在主通道里集合
The search team is gathering in the main tunnel.
好的
Good.
那个生物受伤了
So it is wounded,
所以它变得更加危险
and therefore twice as dangerous.
两人一队
Stay in pairs.
如果看见它，就把你的相位枪
If you see it, concentrate your phaser fire
对准它的头开火
at what appears to be its head.
瞄准，不断开火
Concentrate it, maintain it.
它对激光有一定抵抗性，但是还是会被射伤
It is definitely resistant, but it can be hurt.
如果它能被射伤，就一定能被杀死
If it can be hurt, it can be killed.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
先生们，请查看一下你们的表格
Gentlemen, if you'll examine your charts, please.
我在标记入口26的区域最后一次探测到那个生物
I last located the creature in the area marked adit 26,
朝水平201度方向移动
moving at bearing 201.
我们这些人要从不同方向朝那个区域前进
This particular group will move out beyond that area in all directions,
试图包围它，或许还能活捉它
in an effort to surround it, possibly capture it.
我命令你们杀死它
Your orders are shoot to kill.
时刻注意保护自己
Protect yourself at all times.
乔托少校，分散搜寻队伍
Commander Giotto, disperse your search parties.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
路易斯，达芬奇，带你们的人出去
Lewis, Vinci, take your men out.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
活捉它？我不记得下过这样的命令
Capture it? I don't recall giving any such order.
长官，你确实没有
You did not, sir.
我想或许有那样的机会——
I thought that if the opportunity arose--
我不想再牺牲任何人了
I will lose no more men.
那个生物一经发现就击毙，任务就此完成
The creature will be killed on sight, and that's the end of it.
- 好的，长官 - 史波克先生
- Very well, sir. - Mr. Spock,
我想让你去协助史考特
I want you to assist Scotty
维持临时循环泵的正常运转
in maintaining that makeshift circulating pump.
- 长官，你说什么？ - 你听到我说的话了
- I beg your pardon, sir? - You heard me.
保持反应堆正常运转很重要
It's vital that we keep that reactor in operation.
- 你有丰富的科学知识—— - 长官，我的知识在那里用不上
- Your scientific knowledge-- - Is not needed there, sir.
史考特先生对核反应堆的了解要比我多得多
Mr. Scott has far more knowledge of nuclear reactors than I do.
你知道的
You're aware of that.
史波克先生，你是副指挥官
Mr. Spock, you are second-in-command.
这将是一场危险的围剿
This will be a dangerous hunt.
或许我们都会牺牲
Either one of us, by himself, is expendable.
或许我们都不会有事
Both of us are not.
舰长，大约有100人参与了这场
Captain, there are approximately 1 00 of us engaged in this search
生物搜寻活动
against one creature.
我们俩都被杀的概率是2228.7:1
The odds against you and l both being killed are 2228.7 to one.
2228.7:1？
2228.7 to one?
概率不错，史波克先生
Those are pretty good odds, Mr. Spock.
而且这个概率是很准确的，舰长
And they are, of course, accurate, captain.
当然
Of course.
嗯，我不想用这个词
Well, I hate to use the word,
但是，逻辑上，在那种概率下
but, logically, with those kind of odds,
你还是可以留下来
you might as well stay.
但是，史波克先生，请务必小心
But please stay out of trouble, Mr. Spock.
舰长，我一直就是那样做的
That is always my intention, captain.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长，我是史考特
- Kirk here. - Scotty here, captain.
我的即兴之作刚才失灵了，没法承受负担了
My brilliant improvisation just gave up the ghost. It couldn't stand the strain.
- 你能再修好吗？ - 不行，舰长，它永久性的损坏了
- Can you fix it again? - Negative, captain. It's gone for good.
立即开始将所有殖民地人员撤退到进取号上
Start immediate evacuation of all colonists to the Enterprise.
舰长，不是所有人都要撤走
Not all of them, captain.
我和我的一些主要人员都要留下
I and some of my key personnel are staying.
我们要到下面帮你们
We'll be down to join you.
我们没有足够的相位枪给你们
We don't have enough phasers for you.
那就用棒球棍，我们不想被驱逐出这里，我们要留下
Then we'll use clubs. We're not being chased away from here. We're staying.
好的
Good.
让其他所有人登陆进取号
Get everybody else aboard the Enterprise.
越少人在下面消耗氧气
The fewer people breathing the air down here,
我们剩下的人坚持的时间就越长
the longer the rest of us will hold out.
史考特，还能坚持多久？
How much longer, Scotty?
长官，反应堆将在大约10小时内爆炸
The reactor will go supercritical in about ten hours, sir.
你有10个小时的时间去寻找那个装置
You have that long to find the mechanism.
我们会尽力的
We'll do our best.
史考特，有什么情况及时通知我们
Start feeding us constant status reports, Scotty.
范登堡，让你的人在23层
Vanderberg, you and your crew assemble at level 23,
泰格检查点集合，寇克，通话完毕
Checkpoint Tiger. Kirk, out.
协助进取号安全部队
Team up with the Enterprise security personnel.
他们的装备比你们好，间隔距离不要太大
They're better armed than you. Keep someone in sight at all times.
范登堡，带两个人，穿过那边的通道
Vanderberg, take two men, go through that tunnel there,
和乔托少校汇合
rendezvous with Commander Giotto.
阿佩尔，还有其他人，到那边去
Appel, the rest of the men, go through there,
和奥斯本上尉的队伍汇合
tie up with Lt. Osborne's detail.
我和史波克先生会从中心位置
Mr. Spock and I will control the operation
指挥这次行动，就这些，先生们
from a central point. That's all, gentlemen.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
舰长，我们正被监视着
Captain, we are being watched.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
是直觉吗？
Intuition?
不是，长官，我们正被监视着
No, sir. We're being watched.
舰长，这些通道这一小时内的最新数据
Captain. Fresh readings within the hour, in each of these tunnels.
表上显示这些通道
The chart says both these tunnels converge
都有几千码长
a few thousand yards further.
- 你走左边，我走右边 - 我们分开好吗？
- You take the left, I'll take the right. - Should we separate?
这里有两条通道，我们有两个人
Two tunnels, two of us.
我们分开走
We separate.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
是的，舰长
Yes, captain.
我发现一个放满硅结核的巢穴
I found a whole lair of these silicon nodules of yours.
- 里面有成千上百个 - 确实是那样
- Hundreds of them. - Indeed.
舰长，我想我快要搞清楚了
I find that most illuminating, captain.
一定要小心不要伤到他们
Be absolutely certain you do not damage any of them.
- 给我解释下 - 这还只是我想出的理论
- Explain. - Only a theory I have.
舰长
Captain.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
吉姆
Jim.
吉姆！
Jim!
是的，史波克先生，我没事
Yes, Mr. Spock, all right.
好像塌方了
We seem to have had a cave-in.
- 我可以把你相位出去 - 不，不，你最好不要那么做
- I could phaser you out. - No. No, no, you better not.
任何举动也许会让剩下的墙也塌下来
Any disturbance might bring down the rest of the wall.
而且也不需要那样做
Besides, it isn't necessary.
表上显示这些通道在前方汇合
The chart said that the tunnels meet further on.
好的
Very well.
但是我还是感觉到非常不安
But I find it extremely disquieting
屋檐在你经过的瞬间倒塌
that your roof chose that particular moment to collapse.
请一定要提高警惕
Please proceed with extreme caution.
我要加快速度了
I shall quicken my pace.
好的，史波克先生，我们在另一侧见——
Very well, Mr. Spock. I'll meet you at the other end--
我是寇克
Kirk here.
舰长，我搜寻到一些刚留下的痕迹
Captain, I've just read some fresh signs.
那个生物就在这个区域里
The creature is in this area.
我要进行一次生命探测
I'll take a life-form reading.
不必了，史波克先生，我知道那个生物在哪里
It's not necessary, Mr. Spock. I know exactly where the creature is.
在哪里，舰长？
Where, captain?
离我10码远的地方
Ten feet away from me.
击毙它，舰长，赶紧的
Kill it, captain, quickly.
史波克，它没做任何威胁性的举动
It's not making any threatening moves, Spock.
舰长，你不能那样冒险
You don't dare take the chance, captain.
击毙它
Kill it.
我还以为你想要它活着呢
I thought you were the one that wanted it kept alive,
如果可能的话，活捉它
captured, if possible.
吉姆，你现在很危险
Jim, your life is in danger.
你不能那么冒险
You can't take the risk.
它像是在等待什么
It seems to be waiting.
我提醒你，它可杀了不少人
I remind you, it is a proven killer.
我就快要到了
I'm on my way.
史波克，通话结束
Spock, out.
嗯，我们要做什么，谈判吗？
Well, what do we do, just talk it over?
嗯，你还是会受伤，是不是？
Well, you can be hurt, can't you?
我们就这样坐在这？
We just sit here?
该你了
It's your move.
不，不要开枪
No, no, don't shoot.
到这里来，史波克先生
Come on over, Mr. Spock.
真令人惊叹
Fascinating.
- 它没伤害你吧？ - 没有
- It's made no moves against you? - No.
它像是在等什么
It seems to be waiting.
我试着跟它交谈，但是没什么效果
I tried talking to it, but it didn't do any good.
是的
Yes.
那些通道都通过这里，这里所有的通道
They're all through here, all over the place.
有数千条
Thousands of them.
是的，我发现了
Yes, I see.
你想到了什么吗？
It means something to you?
舰长，或许我知道答案了
Possibly the answer, captain.
但是我不确定
But I'm not certain.
舰长
Captain,
你了解瓦肯族让两个人思想交流的技术吗？
you're aware of the Vulcan technique of the joining of two minds.
你认为你可以了解它的思想？
You think you can get through to that thing?
有可能
Possible.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock,
我知道这是一种可怕的个人心理障碍降低
I know it's a terrible personal lowering of the mental barriers,
但是也有可能…
but if there's a chance...
我要试一试
I'll try.
好痛！
Pain!
我就得到这些信息，舰长
That's all I got, captain.
一波又一波钻心的疼痛
Waves and waves of searing pain.
它痛苦不堪
It's in agony.
“不要杀我”
"No kill I."
那算什么，乞求我们不要杀它？
What is that, a plea for us not to kill it?
或者是它许诺不会杀我们？
Or a promise that it won't kill us?
我不知道，舰长
I don't know, captain.
显然，它通过进入我的思想
Evidently, it gained an immediate knowledge of us
迅速地了解了我们
from its empathy with me.
在我和这个生物思想的短暂接触中
In my brief contact with the creature's mind,
我发现它具有高度的智慧
I discovered it is a highly intelligent,
是非常高等的动物
extremely sophisticated animal,
它感觉疼痛，当然是因为它受的伤
in great pain, of course, because of its wound,
但是它表现得一点也不像受了伤
but not reacting at all like a wounded creature.
它称呼自己“霍塔”
It calls itself a "Horta."
一个霍塔
A Horta.
史波克先生，我们需要拿回阻滞装置
Mr. Spock, we need that retardation mechanism.
你需要再和它建立交流
You must reestablish communications with it.
舰长，它绝不会把那个设备交给我们
Captain, it has no reason to give us the device,
显然它所做的都是想把我们从这颗星球上赶出去
and apparently every reason for wishing us off this planet.
是的，我明白
Yes, I'm aware of that.
如果我们可以赢得它的…
If we could only win its...
…信任
...confidence.
- 麦考伊医生，我是寇克舰长 - 是的，舰长
- Dr. McCoy, this is Captain Kirk. - Yes, captain.
带上你的医疗包，尽快到这里来
Grab your medical kit, and come down here on the double.
这里有一个病人
I've got a patient for you.
有人受伤了吗？发生了什么事？
Is somebody injured? What happened?
不要问了，到23层来
Never mind. Just come down to the 23rd level.
你可以通过三录仪数据找到我们，寇克，结束通话
You'll be led to us by tricorder readings. Kirk, out.
吉姆，我要提醒你这是一个硅基生命
Jim, I remind you that this is a silicon-based form of life.
麦考伊医生的医疗知识完全没有帮助
Dr. McCoy's medical knowledge will be totally useless.
他是个医生，就让他来治疗吧
He's a healer, let him heal.
史波克先生，你必须再和它交流
Mr. Spock, you must reestablish communications.
我想知道为什么它突然开始杀人
I want to know why it suddenly took to murder.
舰长，要达到那种层次的交流
To obtain that kind of communication, captain,
我必须接触到它
it will be necessary to touch it.
我们已经见识过这个生物的破坏能力了
We've seen how the creature destroys.
- 乔托少校 - 我是乔托，舰长
- Lieutenant Commander Giotto. - Giotto here, captain.
- 你们还好吗？ - 好极了
- Are you all right? - Perfectly all right.
- 你们在哪里？ - 我们在通道的尽头
- Where are you? - We're at the end of the tunnel.
现在范登堡先生和他的属下都在这里，他们很生气
Now, Mr. Vanderberg and his men are here, and they're pretty ugly.
我要让他们进来吗？
Should I let them through?
一定不要让他们进来
Under no circumstances allow them in here yet.
麦考伊医生一到那就放他通过
The minute Doc McCoy gets there, send him through.
好的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
谋杀！
Murder!
成千上万的
The thousands.
魔鬼
Devils.
永恒终结了
Eternity ends.
时代的殿堂
The chamber of the ages.
未来的祭坛
The altar of tomorrow.
凶手
Murderers.
阻止他们
Stop them.
杀！
Kill!
把他们击退！
Strike back!
怪物！
Monsters!
这究竟是怎么回事？
What in the name of...?
- 史波克在干什么？ - 它受伤了，很严重
- What is Spock doing? - It's wounded, badly.
你要帮帮它
You've got to help it.
帮它？
Help that?
去看一看
Go take a look.
生命的终结
The end of life.
凶手
Murderers.
你一定是开玩笑
You can't be serious.
这个家伙完全是石头做的
That thing is virtually made out of stone.
帮助它，给它治疗
Help it. Treat it.
我是医生，不是石匠
I'm a doctor, not a bricklayer.
你是医生，它是病人
You're a healer, there's a patient.
这是命令
That's an order.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
告诉它我们想帮助它
Tell it we're trying to help.
还有装置
The mechanism.
我懂的
Understood.
这是生命的终结
It is the end of life.
永恒终结了
Eternity stops.
出去…
Go out...
…到通道里去
...into the tunnel.
去到时代的殿堂
To the chamber of the ages.
哭泣…
Cry...
…可怜的孩子们
...for the children.
小心的行走…
Walk carefully...
…在明天的坟墓中
...in the vault of tomorrow.
好伤悲…
Sorrow...
…为那些被谋害的孩子们
...for the murdered children.
你要寻找的东西就在那里
The thing you search for is there.
去吧
Go.
好伤心
Sadness.
好伤心…
Sadness...
…为万事万物的终结
...for the end of things.
进到通道里面去
Go into the tunnel.
有一条便道
There is a passageway.
快点，快点
Quickly. Quickly.
舰长说要你们在这里等
The captain said for you to wait here,
你们就在这里等着
and here is where you're gonna wait.
那个杀人的怪物就在那里
That murdering monster's in there,
我们要进去杀了它
and we're gonna go in and kill it.
你们要留在这里
You're going to stay here.
好吧，上尉，立即把它传送给我吧
That's right, lieutenant, just beam it down to me immediately
不要管我有什么用途
and never mind what I want it for.
我需要它
I just want it.
现在，快
Now, move.
是时候…
It is time...
…安息了
...to sleep.
一切都结束了
It is over.
失败了
Failure.
凶手们…
The murderers...
…获胜了
...have won.
死亡降临
Death is welcome.
让一切在这里终结吧
Let it end here.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，史波克
Mr. Spock. Spock.
史波克
Spock.
快醒过来
Come out of it.
我在里面发现了这个东西，它完好无损
I found the unit in there. It's in pretty good shape.
我还发现了大约一百万个那种硅结核
And I also found about a million of these silicon nodules.
他们是蛋，是不是？
They're eggs, aren't they?
是的，舰长，那是蛋，就要孵化了
Yes, captain, eggs, and about to hatch.
矿工们一定打穿了孵化室
The miners must have broken into the hatchery.
他们的作业毁坏了上千个蛋，难怪…
Their operations destroyed thousands. No wonder...
在那里，他们来了
There, they're coming.
好吧
All right.
好吧，我们走吧！
All right, let's go!
来吧
Come on.
你在干什么，医生？
How you doing, doc?
我会告诉你
I'll let you know.
- 不，不要开火！ - 杀了它！
- No, don't fire! - Kill it!
谁要开枪谁就死
The first man that fires is dead.
这个怪物杀了我们50个人
That thing has killed 50 of my men.
而你们杀了她几千个孩子
And you've killed thousands of her children.
什么？
What?
那些圆形的硅结核
Those round silicon nodules
那些你们收集和破坏的硅结核
that you've been collecting and destroying,
都是她的蛋
they're her eggs.
史波克先生，告诉他们
Tell them, Mr. Spock.
在这个星球上，霍塔已经生活了许多代
There have been many generations of Horta on this planet.
每隔5万年，整个种族就会灭绝
Every 50,000 years, the entire race dies,
只剩下一个
all but one.
就像是这一个
Like this one.
但是那些蛋也还活着，她照看着它们
But the eggs live, she cares for them,
保护它们，当它们孵化后
protects them. And when they hatch,
她就是它们的母亲，成千上万个孩子的母亲
she is the mother to them, thousands of them.
这个生物是她整个种族的母亲
This creature here is the mother of her race.
霍塔是智慧的
The Horta is intelligent,
和平的，性情温顺的生物
peaceful, mild.
她不反对和你们共享这颗星球
She had no objection to sharing this planet with you
直到你们闯进了她的孵化室，开始破坏她的蛋
till you broke into her nursery and started destroying her eggs.
那时，她就会像所有母亲那样
Then she fought back in the only way she knew how,
用她唯一知道的方法报复
as any mother would fight
当她的孩子身处险境时
when her children are endangered.
我们都不知情，我们怎么能知道呢？
We didn't know. How could we?
但是你说，如果这些蛋孵化出来
But you mean if these eggs hatch,
就会有成千上万的这种生物
there will be thousands of those things
在这里生存？
crawling around down here?
这里是它们生活的地方
This is where they live.
它们开拓通道，靠溶解岩石，获取营养物质
They digest rock. They tunnel for nourishment.
而且它们是最没攻击性的生物
And they are the most inoffensive of creatures.
它们没有恶意
They harbour ill will toward no one.
现在，看，我们可以生产钚介钼
Now, look, we have pergium to deliver.
是的，我知道了
Yes, I know.
给你循环泵
Here's your circulating pump.
嗯，你原来抱怨这颗星球
Now, you've complained that this planet
是一座矿产珍宝屋
is a mineralogical treasure house
如果你有设备能够开采的话
if you had the equipment to get at it.
嗯，先生们，霍塔在岩石中穿梭移动
Well, gentlemen, the Horta moves through rock
就像我们在空气中移动，而且它们留下了通道
the way we move through air, and it leaves tunnels.
它们是这宇宙中最伟大的天然矿工
The greatest natural miners in the universe.
看起来我们可以达成协议
Seems to me that we could make an agreement,
以作权宜之计
reach a modus vivendi.
它们开拓出通道，你们采集矿产进行生产
They tunnel, you collect and process,
你们的生产产生盈利会增加无数倍
and your process operation would be a thousand times more profitable.
听起来很不错，如果事情真能那样发展的话
Sounds all right, if it'll work.
除了一件事情
Except for one thing.
霍塔受伤很严重
The Horta is badly wounded.
- 它或许会死掉 - 它不会死
- It may die. - It won't die.
天啊，吉姆，我开始觉得自己都能“治愈”雨天了
By golly, Jim, I'm beginning to think I can cure a rainy day.
- 你能帮助它吗？ - 帮助它？我把它治好了
- Can you help it? - Helped it? I cured it.
你用了什么方法？
How?
我让星舰给我传送下一百磅热混凝土
I had the ship beam down a hundred pounds of that thermo-concrete.
你知道，就是我们用来建造应急避难所的那种东西
You know, the kind we use to build emergency shelters out of.
主要成分就是硅
It's mostly silicon.
所以我就把它倒到伤口上
So I just troweled it into the wound,
在伤口愈合之前，它就像是一张创可贴
and it'll act like a bandage until it heals.
来看一看，和新的一样
Take a look. It's good as new.
史波克先生，我需要你再次和霍塔交流
Mr. Spock, I'm gonna have to ask you to get in touch with the Horta again.
告诉她我们的提议
Tell her our proposition.
她和她的孩子们可以任意挖掘通道
She and her children can do all the tunnelling they want,
我们的人会移走矿物
our people will remove the minerals,
双方都不会干扰对方的活动
and each side will leave the other alone.
- 你觉得她会答应吗？ - 舰长，提议看起来很合逻辑
- Do you think she'll go for it? - It seems logical, captain.
霍塔有很好的逻辑性
The Horta has a very logical mind.
在和人类进行密切交流后
And after close association with humans,
我发现我的好奇心增强了不少
I find that curiously refreshing.
舰长，星舰准备脱离轨道
Ship ready to leave orbit, captain.
- 已经驶入预订航线 - 很好，史波克先生
- Course laid in. - Very good, Mr. Spock.
首席工程师范登堡在频道一待命
Chief Engineer Vanderberg standing by on channel one.
好的，你好，首席？我是寇克
Fine. Yes, chief? Kirk here.
舰长，只是想告诉你那些蛋已经开始孵化了
Just wanted to tell you the eggs have started to hatch, captain.
那些小家伙做的第一件事就是去挖掘通道
The first thing the little devils do is start to tunnel.
我们已经勘探到了新的钚介钼矿了
We've already hit huge new pergium deposits.
我害怕告诉你我们发现了
I'm afraid to tell you how much gold and platinum
多少黄金、铂和稀土元素
and rare earths we've uncovered.
我听到这个很高兴，首席
I'm delighted to hear that, chief.
一旦霍塔妈妈告诉她的孩子们要去找什么
Once Mother Horta tells her kids what to look for,
你们都会富甲一方的
you people are going to be embarrassingly rich.
你也知道，霍塔心肠不坏
You know, the Horta aren't so bad
只要你习惯了和他们在一起
once you get used to their appearance.
是的，真的是那样，寇克，谢谢你做的一切
Well, that's about it, Kirk. Thanks for everything.
这是我们的荣幸，首席，寇克，通话结束
Our pleasure, chief. Kirk, out.
真好奇
Curious.
范登堡首长说的关于霍塔的话
What Chief Vanderberg said about the Horta
正是霍塔妈妈对我说的话
is exactly what the mother Horta said to me.
她发现人类的面目很有攻击性
She found humanoid appearance revolting,
但是她认为她会习惯的
but she thought she could get used to it.
嗯，她做到了，是不是？
Oh, she did, did she?
嗯，告诉我，她是不是碰巧对你的耳朵做过评价？
Now, tell me, did she happen to make any comment about those ears?
没有
Not specifically.
但是我确实有了明确的印象，她觉得耳朵
But I did get the distinct impression she found them
是人类最有吸引力的部位
the most attractive human characteristic of all.
我不忍心告诉她只有我有这么独特的耳朵——
I didn't have the heart to tell her that only I have--
她真的喜欢你的耳朵吗？
She really liked those ears?
舰长，霍塔是具有相当高智慧
Captain, the Horta is a remarkably intelligent
和无可挑剔品味的敏感生物
and sensitive creature with impeccable taste.
因为她称赞了你
Because she approved of you.
真的，船长，我的谦逊——
Really, captain, my modesty--
史波克先生，不要做经不起推敲的言论
Does not bear close examination, Mr. Spock.
我发现你越来越像人类了
I suspect you're becoming more and more human all the time.
你…
You...
舰长，我不能再在这里受侮辱了
Captain, I see no reason to stand here and be insulted.
以曲速率2前进
Ahead, warp factor 2.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/